hi all I'm audible and visible guys good evening great so let me share my
screen do let me know if my screen share also works fine great let me start
five minutes timer
yes how many of you did went home and tried or like I after the class tried
you know reopening that project and checking on that can man board have you
all gone through the code base
okay so how is the experience I say in turn project his timers he has j's are
you able to understand and great some with Kabir we can check it we have four
minutes or else if you're not able to complete informants we can take it you
know after class that's all that's also fine right we can we'll take it post
class let's take it that way great some with them it can you raise a PR or show
it to everyone okay great so let me open this link so he has deployed yes let's
see what somebody has done
well this looks cool so he had played around you know with CSS and made
something looking make it look cool cool so if you see to do in progress and
QA and done so I really appreciate this one because you played around with some
of the styles and you know on hover of this button other than take you know
great so this thing you can fix it some it's still like you can make it look
further better this empty space I think you missed some padding on the right
okay I'm not exactly sure where it is coming from but you can address this
one's okay that's a small thing and then let's say if I make task one you can
also make this rounded one let's say to do okay he had given a create button can
you see this guys instead of giving alt button so we can also he has created a
create button like on click of this thing I think the activity will take
place right let's say okay nice another pop-up which shows that hey ticket got
created instead of alert box where we were trying to delete it he has done
this now let's say if I try to edit this one hey edit button enabled for the
ticket ID cool so let's I update this 101 and I close this let's see if this
all things have been updated in the local storage too
okay to do right great so that got updated now it also has a status and
everything fine now let's see if I move to in progress nothing is there a good
in progress double-click it I can see everything now let's say I have another
task let's say zero or task zero two and I say in progress create fine let's
say if I filter by zero two cool zero one great so this was really cool you
know add on some bit appreciate it so guys do you like this I'll bookmark this
one in the class so this is an add-on from the features that some with tried
it hopefully everyone explored this you know if someone want to add more
features on to this one he can you can talk to him if one thing you can do
somebody said share your kit link in group it's up to it's your personal
project maybe what this onto your resume if you want to share with everyone
that's okay or else anyone some someone can take inspiration from this deployed
website they can add on their own things right but I've do I did I make justice
that I explained everything properly but everyone can do you know built on their
own side of things right so great this is really appreciated appreciable so one
thing I did it guys is that for you okay I pushed another code like I believe
like you can go through this code and understand this one initially I was
talking about portfolio project right like I made some dummy data I did some
starting in so currently we haven't moved to react so let's make it a simple
portfolio project then you can improve on so if you see if you see this is a
project earlier I have shown at the starting of the when you started no for
this code base I have pushed into this gate of repo I have added so now let's
say you have built two projects right one is weather project and another is
Kanban what if you link those both things here and on click of this thing
you redirect to let's say Kanban board or any other board okay so I'm giving
you this thing you also link your gate of repos lead code LinkedIn and whatever
you have write it down your things just update the content that would be enough
okay update the content in the HTML file everything will be auto done and you can
add your description so that you are a web developer a portfolio is built
parallel okay group of projects that you need the tech whatever you need I am
moving pushing this code so if you see I have added some changes I'll move that
so that everyone can use this one let me open a new terminal
get commit
okay so one thing I'll do is that I'll you know I'll bookmark this for showing
some other parts like when I take this I did
okay cool great on some bit so I hope everyone go and you know try it out put
your hands on hands around you can see this how this is working fine or not one
thing why I wanted to test this one is that let's say if I make it responsive
cool so cool I can see it's working fine great one so one thing you can do here
one suggestion some bit just you know make this in a in a button like you can
explore like how can you like a hamburger button or anything okay this
this only this thing like you can use media query and just add one more thing
like instead of horizontal you can make it vertical or any anything like as you
like it only filter by okay great other than that everything looks cool good one
so guys let's get started with today's class I think we are on time I see good
amount good amount of people but can you can anyone ping in whatsapp group for a
second that we are getting started with today's class
okay
great
thank you guys so let's let's get started with do let me know once you can see the
iPad I'll share this iPad
so it's loaded right okay good now I hope everyone can see this and I'm
okay good now I hope everyone can see this and let's get started with today's
class guys so we'll talk about agenda and what we are going to cover and how
it is going to be so today's and next class will be basically focused on
something called as machine coding so these are the questions that are used
for LLD interviews so I'll share you one of the repo where you know you have to
practice a different side of LLD equations now those LLD equations have
to be solved by both using vanilla JS and react JS so one is using HTML CSS
JS now this using again simple framework or library okay so the same set of
questions you should be able to solve both things because this will be the
interview specific projects that are you are building or we are learning will be
helpful to build our portfolio and also for the practice purpose to get into an
understanding of all the concepts we are learning and how we'll apply okay so
this is what our plan is going to be for the current today's class and
upcoming next class and in this right currently we'll focus on today we'll be
focusing on building two things one is a counter component like it's really
basic we'll get started with really basic example counter component like you
click off button you should be able to increase the account on the click of
minus but we should be able to decrease account and similarly you can also add
an form element which can help you to increase by decrease by value and then
there will be a star rating star rating component is something like you can see
on many apps right if you go for any app if you want to give a rating or on your
Ola over or any Amazon flipkart any site that you see online they always can
take the rating as a basic feedback because no one is willing to write a
content full feedback so rating is component is something really used so
we'll see how we can build it using HTML CSS and JS so once we do this we'll go
into the next class where we'll learn something like OTP how do you enter OTP
then comment section how do you build comment section right and then there is
another thing that we explore but this is for the next class currently we'll be
learning today applying our knowledge to this one like how would you actually
approach an interview okay and other than this thing there's a one concept
that I have to cover but few people say that it has been already covered few
people say it not it was not covered so I just want to know whether do you
understand something called event propagation how many of you understand
this word even propagation see four six seven okay great so some someone told me
that Sasha has covered this one so I just got confused okay no worries if it
is not covered we'll get started with even propagation then once we understand
this then we'll come to this too I hope the basic agenda is clear is like what
we are going to do it today so let's let's get started with the even
propagation then yeah yeah yeah yeah so firstly like you know in the DOM right
whatever DOM tree is created now whenever let's say DOM is looking like
let's say if I try to down a particular tree it looks like something like this
right if we try to replicate let's say this tree itself let's say I have a
particular level div container inside that let's say I have another two divs
okay this is something you can say root node then let's say I give the naming
convention one then two then three right let's say this is zero this is one this
is two then you have this is let's say three right let's make it as two three
fine
zero okay in mistake say this is one this is two this is three then you have
well let's say a span here an image here okay let's say this is four this is five
then again in this between let's say you have video here then you have input here
okay six seven now what we exactly meant by propagation is that whenever
whenever we click whenever we click something let's say we click on this
particular day or for the matter let's say even HTML whenever we click on a
whole page there are two types of propagation does happen there are two
types of propagation that happen one is in words second one is outwards now how
does we can resist like let's say you have a boxes this way our parent-child
relationship let's say this is a grandparent this is parent then this is
child now whenever you have this sort of children relationship when we say
grandparent parent-child let's say this is a HTML this is a div and this is
something like a span no whenever by default right what whatever the default
nature of HTML is that you know all the events usually bubbles up this is the
default nature default nature right whenever let's say what if what if you
had event listener added here when you had an event listener here okay and by
any chance by any chance if you click by any chance if you click on a parent
right let's let's see this with an example but there are you know I will
draw the will go to the example and we'll see basically what I'm trying to
say that even propagation happens in two ways which is one is called as
bubbling one is called as capturing okay when we say bubble in general we mean to
say that it comes out it bubbles out when you click a child element you will
be also be able to hear in the parent element okay but that's what it says
that like whenever you click a child element parent element will also be able
to listen that click but what capturing says is that if you click parent element
child element will also be able to listen like it works from this bubble up
capturing so we'll see by default nature is something called as bubbling okay by
default is about let's say this actual you know using HTML CSS for the better
understanding we'll come back to this diagram in a minute let me create a class
of 17 in JS part only folder class 17 which I have simple index start HTML
inside this let me generate auto HTML part then we'll build a simple dip like
the diff and I'll say this as a grandparent let's say okay inside this
let's say I have Dave parent so I have Dave child okay simple three dips that I
talked about now what I'll do here is that I'll create a script and okay
before this let's add some CSS to this so that will be able to identify these
boxes okay let's say body for this one I'll say display flex align item center
justify content center and have some padding across of 20 pixel okay fine or
let's say I can say 20 percent fine and now what I'll do is that I'll give you
know like a basic CS styles for this one so that we are able to play around with
this content okay let me pick up this part of style for each diff I added
minimum height and minimum width and padding around it okay let's let's go to
open this one and browser no okay this is what we were able to build out of
that but now what we'll do is that we'll also do something like we'll add what is
child what is parent and everything let's let me do this say child parent
grandparent let's say this reflects yeah fine now what I'll do simply is that I'll
add basic listeners to all of them now to add this listeners what we will be
doing it is like fairly simple getting all these elements okay getting an
access to the element let's say const I say that grandparent document dot query
selector inside this since it's an ID I'm trying to access my ID I'll say that
grandparent okay const then parent say document dot query selector I say
hashtag parent again const child
document dot query selector child okay so I had created a prank to access all
the elements which are created and no HTML so let's once we have this access
to this dom elements what I'll do is like I'll add a listener to each of them
let's say and event listener and I'll specifically listen to this click event
inside this click event I won't be doing anything but I'll console log let's say
console dot log I'll say that this is a grandparent grandparent clicked then
let's say I copy this I paste again twice I'll see this as a parent I'll
convert this as a parent I'll put it as a child I'll keep it as a child
so any doubts guys on this till now what we have done this is a pretty basic right
what we have achieved here like straightforward creator three days box
inside box inside box how we were able to create box we know that using a box
model will be able to achieve that and I've just tried to put those elements
in center using these properties and I tried to get access add event listeners
to them now let's see what's happening in the console okay I come to the
console now I just want you to know check on this one behavior what happens
like if I click here if I click here on the grandparent let's see what's what
we are able to see output do you see when we click it grandparent clicked is
something out we got it in console as an output this is the reason why this has
been effective because we added a listener to the grandparent and we
directly console dog but now what if what if I go and click on a parent if I
click on a parent now if you see both parent and grandparent got clicked no I
didn't click anything on a grandparent I didn't click any button on this
grandparent but grandparent automatically got clicked now this
particular feature is called as bubbling that am clicking something
innermost child element now all the parents are also getting clicked
automatically when the listeners are attached to it okay now let me show you
again if I click child now child they click then parent then grandparent are
you able to see this bubbling effect like how this bubbling effect is
happening so this is what an even propagation that by default whenever you
click any child element parent if parent is having a listener or any
subsequent parent is having listener those are those parents will be always
listening like when whenever you have this sort of listeners let parent have
it they'll listen this I hope you understand that how at even bubbling is
how even propagation happens in even bubbling and by default the nature of
this particular events whatever by default are even bubbling format okay
this point is clear now let's let's explore what is capturing now if you
see if I hover on add event listener then okay now if you see here what's
happening here they say that in the event add event listener first is type
when I say type it is talking about the event type like click mouse over mouse
mouse leave and everything to or like any sort of events then it it takes the
listener object or the function that we had now then there are multiple sets of
options like optional options that you can give we haven't given any option yet
but this is working as expected but there is a one thing that you can play
around with there's a one thing you can always play around with is that let's
say if I give here false okay let's say if I give here false what happens let's
say if I go and click it here still nothing is nothing is you know no
problem everything works fine everything is looking good but what if I go on to
give false everywhere
let's say this is a third parameter that I am adding in this add event
let's see if it's still affecting anything when I click child child is
printed parent is printed a grandparent is printed now did anyone observe
anything any change there do you see any change guys
is there any change no change right now what this third parameter is talking
about so firstly when we say this event listener right takes three things first
thing is like type of event then it takes something like a function a call
back function what we'll do once listeners click then you have use
capture now whenever you say that use capture by default is use capture is
set to the false the reason is that by default when you said use capture as
false it works in the event bubbling fashion okay now let's see if I convert
okay now let's see if I convert all of them into true let's say if I convert
them into true that I am using in the capture format now if I want to
propagate events or anything that according to like you in the capture
format even capturing let's see how this works now if you see if I click on a
child
no if I click on a child you see here first grandparent got clicked okay then
parent got clicked then child got clicked so event whenever you click
innermost element the bubbling happened from top most to bottom earlier it was
happening from target element to top most now it is happening from top most
to the target element now even if I click parent grandparent and parent
will be clicked is this flow clear guys how capture and bubbling differs like
one is going from a target element to the top the other one is come coming
from the top to the target element that's a basic difference between event
bubbling and capturing opposite to each other by default you'll seen bubbling
nature now what if what if you don't want this behavior to happen why like
how these there is any way that we can stop this event flow like sometimes you
don't want to leverage this flow like if there is something that we can stop it
so for in order to stop this execution a like what you have is like you have one
of the ability called stop event propagation okay now how can you do
that how can you do that let's say if I have here event okay I say that event
dot stop propagation once I call this event inside the listener I mean call
back function let's say when you when you are exiting callback callback
function let's see if this is working fine now what if we are able to stop the
propagation and we are in the capture phase if I click child what should be
the output we are in even capture phase it should start from the topmost
element and come to the child you know target element grandparent parent then
okay how many of you are agreeing with Arun Sambit okay great now let's see if
I click on a child still do you see do you see child didn't even print it though
we added listener to the child though we added listener to the child since we
had stop propagation in the parent element itself and the parent element
itself we had stop propagation so it didn't let this listener this console
lock print or it didn't let execute this callback function is this clear how this
event propagation works like doesn't matter where you click what you do if
in the flow it stops stops like that flow completely now let's say even if I
click let's convert this into bubbling format and let's see what's the
difference now when I'm trying to bubble it now if I click on a child again it
goes from target element to parent or topmost element now when I click child
let's say if you see child and parent got printed but grandparent didn't
print because we stopped propagation there itself so I hope this point is
clear like how stop propagation works so the reason behind right why we don't
use this even propagation we should know this concept but if you see this like
how events are flowing how the events have been triggered it's really tricky
to handle or you know build a code on this one so it is suggested that you
try to you know you can take advantage to it but if you are really great with
but if someone beginner comes or someone new to this project it would be really
difficult for him to understand how bubbling and you know like capturing is
working up to an extent of a whole when a whole project is built on that sort of
idea okay so it's good to build what if stop propagating at a grandparent and
it will block the parent okay let's see this let's say this I cut it here and
make it true okay
no case I'm in the capturing phase I know what if I click on a child element
what could be the out of output of it I'm in capturing face just think of it
some bit think of it triparty
okay yeah so only GP people just like let's say if I click on a child if you
see only grandparent got clicked even if I'm clicking child or parent okay
anything so that's how even propagation works so it is not suggested to play
around with this event bubbling and you know capturing at a bigger extent
because that's confuses people even it's really difficult to build project
according to this okay I hope this points is clear guys how even bubbling
capturing works and even propagation works if someone asked you into would
would you be able to answer taking the simple example just like from target
element to complete outwards or complete outwards to the target element
two flows by default it bubbles up any doubts on this topic guys anyone having
any challenge understanding this topic can we go ahead with machine coding cool
so let's say simply we can say that when when we put an event prop will block
all the child yeah propagation will block it however you define depending on
the concept whether coming inverse or going outwards it will stop outgoing
thing counter dot HTML let's say I have this counter dot HTML firstly I'll show
you what I exactly mean like how we want to build this counter let me open my new
other repository and launch it and show it to this second guys
no this is really basic don't judge me on my CSS but if you see it here can you
guys see this let me know if you can see the screen okay can you see this on
screen okay now so what happens in many of the machine coding runs or what I
faced it from my experience or I'll tell you a few things what happens right some
times in some use cases you may not be given a complete problem to solve you
will be given a partially completed problem where you have to understand the
document they give and the code it is already written so the it will have a
combination of such that you understand the code and fix the issues in the code
existing like they'll create a box in the existing code okay so firstly will
understand like hey can you fix this issue can you fix that issue once you do
this you'll also have an ability like next would thing would be like you add
on some features to the existing project okay so that's a one type of LLD rounds
whereas other types of LLD rounds are basically based on building a simple
components where end-to-end things you have to build in one hour or given a
time there are some times that they'll give will they'll give you a use case
where you have to build end-to-end things so you can't they won't stop you
from taking advantage of library or mostly they if they are it's a pair
programming they'll stop you from using AI tools though they'll allow you to do
it in company but they might not allow you to do it in interview process is this
clear what type of rounds are expected at LLD level in front end okay so if I
try to summarize again like simple thing complete
scratch
to full feature this will be small questions there will be some incomplete
projects
incomplete projects deep so I'll tell you what sort of skills are tested on
this thing okay so here your skills of like how are you trying to build
everything like from end to end when you're doing end to end right so your
thinking process will be common for both the things but when you build end to end
project right this is like more important around this will be like for
the initial levels screening okay once you are able to only clear this will
come to incomplete project where you will be tested on debugging like how we
are able to debug existing code because you have to fix defects debugging is
important for fixing defects and understanding existing code okay once
you're able to do it then creating or building
add-on implementation okay here more leaf when you do from scratch clean code
clean code should be opted okay now but I hope you understood these two points
like how LLD goes when it comes to front end right there will be there can be two
rounds and there can be both the rounds for some companies okay some might give
complete scratch one some people might give incomplete project and try to help
you know you should have been working and understand the existing code and
then debug it and complete it that's the reason why that is the reason why I
also parallelly debug and show you that how I'm doing it whether it is in
browser or whether it in visual studio code okay I hope you follow each and
everything okay guys is that clear no now comes the point is that now let's
say there is some interview interview when you go and someone says that hey
you have to build this you have to build this this encounter he won't talk much
he'll say he'll say that have to build this now you go and test it out let's
say if I say increment by five okay and I click on let's say plus so it is added
by five each time if I reduce each time it is reducing by five what if I go on
increase by six no it is increasing by six but the route the thing you have to
work on is each time they are updating the item is not being reset to zero but
it is keep on adding to that existing value okay and on click of reset the
value is becoming zero is this clear is the functionality wise now you guys
will help me out to build end-to-end a simple HTML CSS and JS now you have to
help me out build this one now first and foremost thing what we'll do is that
we'll build it HTML okay no can anyone okay you guys help me out what we want
to do it I'll just open a file let's say this is an in default HTML file no let's
make this a div container let's say our Dave with a container class keep on
pitching it guys now why have this container what should I contain inside
this container
okay counter text h1 counter text okay let's say if I make this h1 okay counter
okay cool then then yeah great guys next one before input you have something a
number before label also guys do you see output value you see this output
value in orange color how would you address that one so Abhishek Pratap has
given everything no let's say can I say this way they've dev dot let's say
hashtag number and I give it zero let me open or show preview also on the site so
that you can see step by step what we are doing currently we have built this
one now then we have input value right let me build this one I'll say there's
a div a simple live I'll have like increment or decrement by
once I have written this then I can have input element
okay and type would be what could be the type guys number right number so that
you have a element anything you can add it but you cannot type down anything
string well like string data where it is a data now what's the next thing plus
and minus button div then inside two buttons right let's say I have div then
inside that I'll have button and let's say ID would be add and inside that add
to give it I'll give it as plus icon then button hashtag subtract then I'll
give minus let's say this one get the better sheet now after this you have
reset but isn't it now let's say I have again button hashtag reset I have this
reset okay I hope this is clear a basic pretty simple thing anyone having any
doubts this thing everyone would be able to do this one right if someone asks you
to build this layout pretty simple straight forward now now comes the
styles let's say if we are trying to add styles here itself for the class
purpose I'm adding it here okay now let's say what you are seeing here okay
container let's say a container so display is flex okay I see all the items
went justify content center and center
cool now do you guys see any issues here
okay can can anyone fix this so whatever is comments I get it I'll try to add
that one other people will help me out okay flex direction column let's say I
have flex direction column cool now now comes the next thing let me show you
this
no for buttons okay there's a margin and okay let's say I have a margin of 10
pixel okay fine now then border 2 pixel solid black okay then gap of 10 okay
let's say if I give gap of 10 pixel okay good no border radius of one rim
let's say I convert this into rem units itself let's say 0.7 rim I keep it a 0.7
rim so 0.2 rim okay cool now okay height 25 VH
the height VH 25 VH is not helpful make it 45 good no a basic set of colors a
basic set of colors like let's say hashtag firstly let's let's make it
style that reset button okay let's style that reset button it's come step by step
going from the bottom reset button
busy color coral button blue okay let's say hashtag reset background color
coral cool no after that
let's make this lighter one okay let's add up order radius of 0.15
rim this is not enough let's make it one rim itself okay now this one thing
and okay let's make this hashtag ID
fine now the color for this content ID number is left okay so what color I have
coral well that's a tomato fine so I hope this this is something orange okay
anything yes I hope this is pretty basic and clear right whenever you see a
layout you will be able to imagine how that layout was built and what it might
need to require to build that one okay I hope that amount of confidence you as
you guys are getting it now by now okay now comes the JS path logic part now
let's say how would you approach this one let's I have a script tag here
itself okay once I have the script tag now let me know what I want to write
because this is something that you are going to teach me out I'm not going to
teach you out because this is pretty simple example get the access to the
required buttons help me out help me out let's say I have add
const subtract
then you have reset okay okay now how can I get access to this one document
query selector inside this I have to give something no tell me or guess what
I should add like for the ad if I want to get at okay this is the suggestions
hashtag add and then let's say hashtag subtract okay then you have something
like reset okay so this buttons are clear enough to us now you have input
element also now in order to get input element let's say I can say const I can
say something like counter underscore increment or decrement okay document
dot query selector okay I'll get an access to this one as we don't have here
anything entered now let's give some information here okay let's give
something ID as increment or underscore decrement okay let's select this ID
hashtag okay then we had const counter document dot query selector inside this
if you see I have number hashtag number cool so guys did we get access to all
the things that we need now great now what could be the next step what could
be the next step what would be the next step
add click listeners to add okay add event listeners to let's say add dot add
event listener now let's say I added a event listener here then do I need to
add even further it further more event listeners right now let's say I have to
add further more listeners now what all event listeners I need for subtract and
then reset anything else guys and do we need to listen to click for all of them
now now comes the role play now tell me what we have to do now let's say on
click of add what we'll do let's say I have a event okay no on click of I event
let's say I have one user clicked on plus what should happen on add get the
value from the input add to the update the value of the number with the
counter plus input value great the it's it's great how do I get access get value
from the number that's my question that's my question how do you get it
value from that input value what is the where that input get attribute works
fine but on the form elements you can directly get using one of the value on
event or target dot value we won't be having that because on that's a click
event is for add button okay now few people suggested that let's say I say
current number if I say current number and I just keep that counter okay I get
the counter dot value whether this will give me the value current value
no so that's that's present in the div that's present in the div isn't it so we
can get it in a text okay once this is done how can we convert this one into
integer how can we convert this into integer percent
this is clear like how current number we are able to get access to this
particular number now let's say I have another variable called once increment
or decrement by let's say I have this one now how would you get this
can I do this increment decrement dot value
right input dot value that's how I convert this also pass end not
necessarily needed but let's for the safe side no so we got the two numbers
now how we should be able to update it how we should be able to update it same
thing counter dot in a text equal to current number plus increment decrement
right so I hope you guys all agree with this one let's say default number I put
it as one now and let's say I also have here let's say this is a zero by default
and here inside this value let me give it one as a number okay no once I click
this what should be the value of this particular value once I click plus now
it should be updated as one right as per our idea let's say this is working fine
if I convert into two it's working fine three great guys now now comes a
subtract part isn't it same things that we have to use it only one operation
that we have to change
just change the sign cool no let's say I update this then I am able to reduce it
cool but I want to do something I want to handle one of the use case you guys
have to help me out I don't want negative outputs negative numbers if
let's say if I my current number is by 3 and I'm decrementing by 5 reset it to 0
reset it to 0 but don't give me negative okay so can we do it this way like if I
can write this condition if only greater than 0 execute this statement else apply
zero a basic condition
no if I'm trying to reduce it let's say it is always on the zero if I have
further it can reduce to 2 1 it won't let's let us take the negative number
this is clear now on click of reset what we should be doing it let's say I have
this number and also let's say I have this number now what should be the two
things that we should be doing on the click of reset make it 0 input value
equal to default no input value equal to default let's get that input value
equal to default let's make that dot value equal to 0 once we make this reset
button then also counter dot in a text equal to 0
to 0 let's let's make this input value in y1 let's see this if this is working
fine I have this random number let's say 3 then I increase it then I'm reducing
it if I click reset this is working fine so how does it feel guys is it simple
like machine coding would be able to do this sort of problems if asked in
interview straight forward and simple isn't it so now now I have one more
interesting question that we can pick it up okay this is going to be bit
tricky okay let me show you that give me a second how it would look like
but great guys you are able to follow up I'm really proud of that point now you
are able to see the star component now again some basic HTML CSS but now I have
this I have when I click this I'm getting count as 2 if I'm clicking this
getting count as 3 then 2 and then 1 okay I hope this is you are able to get
it how this is have to be built and what is the logic behind it okay so one thing
I'll do is that since this is the last topic for today's class I am making it
much lighter today or else we can pick it up one more question if we want to
but what we'll do is that I'll give a five minutes break you guys figure it
out how you can build this one we'll come back and we'll build okay some
which says let's pick two three more I'll give it as a homework some bit
because I have a number of questions that you can solve and number of
questions that you have to solve because people were asking me like they need a
few set of questions 2.5 that would be a part of a homework what currently we are
building like to build like whole thing you should be able to give 2.5 okay so
you should be able to figure out like how like if I'm clicking on the left
part of but the so you have to figure it out how we could be able to do this but
let's come back okay I'll give a five minutes a break then we'll come back and
build this one okay
today is going to be shorter class I believe you know so starting the timer
guys okay seven minutes I can give it no issues since classes shorter today okay
you
guys I hope everyone is back
ok so Pradeep was asking me to re-explain the subtract part so Pradeep the only thing that
change we had done in subtract is that I don't want to address negative values in the output
so whenever I'm doing a subtraction between current number and increment decrement by
I'm only if it is greater than if subtraction is greater than 0 then I'm doing a subtraction
or I'm resetting it the value of 0 I hope this point is clear Pradeep ok still it is not clear
so let's say if you see my current number is 5 and I'm trying to reduce what should be the
value if I click on minus 4 then 3 then 2 and then 1 then what could be the next value 0 now
if I try to subtract further minus 1 minus 2 right but if I am clicking it again do you see
the value is getting subtracted further no right so I was trying to handle this edge case
where I'm saying that in output what if you don't want the negative values so I was saying
that whenever I'm updating the counter inner text value this inner text value I was saying
that hey whenever you are doing a subtraction compare this is a tertiary operator I hope you
understand tertiary operator how does it work I'm checking if the subtraction is only greater
than 0 then subtract and assign this value to the counter or else assign 0 to it like even if I'm
reducing minus 1 the value becomes minus 1 so it is resetting it with 0 I hope this point is
clear how this works this is equivalent to if condition then if and else condition simple if
else condition okay great so guys let's start get started with other example if you are still
interested in pursuing another example we'll pick it up OTP today then we'll have further examples
in next class okay star dot HTML okay let's make it star rating okay let's close this let's open
this no default HTML 5 this again as you suggested me earlier I need your help again so you are in
interview again you are given a discretion so what could be your approach firstly let's build
HTML itself let's build HTML itself firstly guys is everyone the class one by one thing
let's say I'll start typing it down div with a container okay once I have the container inside
that I have same h1 tag as earlier with the star component then I'm supposed to have a list of
stars inside the dev let's say dev dot class star container okay we'll come to stars how can you
build the stars and we'll come to that now let's say next time next thing we have is something like
ratings count okay font also we can leverage right agree now then you have something like
let's say h2 inside that I can say that ratings count and I'll say this way and I'll keep the
value let's span zero to ID I'll give us count ID for just for reference now now let's let's
explore this one how does how does this should work firstly for icons if you go to font awesome
and go to the icons I say star I have this star icon whatever we need right we have fs
solid fs star both things are there but do you know so how many of you understand difference
between ascii and utf it how many of you understand difference between ascii and utf it
doesn't even know what ascii values are or what utf values are okay so ascii values are in general
starts from a to Z capital A to capital Z and zero to nine so all these numbers are ranging
in ascii value so basically initially when applications were built mostly they have
based on ascii support okay what whatever you see that you know like deep by default ascii
was something was considered but utf8 was like used for global which has a 8 encoding bit where
you can go and build you know as many characters you want like if it's a Chinese or Telugu or
Hindus Hindi scripts all those things can be still written on the websites and right they can be
leveraged or anything so such kind of things can be encoded in the utf8 that's the reason why
whenever you see in the meta care set they say that this particular HTML is utf8 compatible it's
not only ascii compatible but it is utf8 like a wrapper where you can also write Hindi Telugu
English right whenever you go for if you remember when we were using when we're trying to use a
font family for like when we are learning font family we saw that every different type
of language can be rendered in HTML and HTML should be able to understand and render it right
so that that's that's where utf8 comes into the role I hope this difference is clear basic
difference like ascii goes from A to Z A to Z and zero to nine but utf8 is much more than like
everything comes into it okay just an encoding but now what I was trying to point out is that if
you want to use font awesome that's very good idea but there is something also like utf8 icons
HTML let's say if you go and see right miss all the icons there are different sort of icons by
default HTML will provide you we didn't explore this one yet but we are exploring this one because
sometimes this like interviewer might ask like what other than font awesome what is a default
HTML provided icons if you see in the utf8 you will see in different cassettes like ascii win
ISO symbols utf8 here you will be able to see that all the Greek letters punctuation marks currency
symbols letter like number forms so all those all of those things concerned are emojis are also
there like whatever emojis you need to that's by default you'll be you'll have under this utf8
encoding okay so how let's say if you see here spade right now in order to render the spade they
have different like they use ampersand symbol for your letting it know that hey we are trying to
use the this dex code okay I mean we are trying to you write something in a utf8 then you use
hashtag or this one symbol to depend whether you are using Dex or hex code okay here if you
see for the star symbol we are having something black star and white star do you see this black
star and white star so star symbol is by default being provided here so let's let's try to use
this and let's see how we can use this one also what I'll do is that I'll copy this Dex code
I'll copy this Dex code and then I'll create a diff of let's say star into 5 okay I created
a five diffs of star and I'll paste it let's say ampersand hashtag or do you see that star
is coming by default let me copy this okay yeah it works in any platform because it is
browser compatible now if I if I change this cassette to ask I still it is working because
it in you know modern browsers it they pass it okay but by default these are utf8 compatible
and most of the HTMLs are come utf8 compatible like you go for any project and you go for the
headers the basic cassette would be utf8 compatible I hope this point is clear okay you go and pick
it up anything today's world they uses now once we have built this now comes the main CSS part
let's help me out with the basic CSS that we have to apply here
it's the same sort of CSS right on a container I'll apply same still display flex
align items also let's say flex direction column align items center justify content center okay
no but if I don't give this if I do I need this doesn't really matter but let me know this star
icons do you see the star icons as aligned as we need it okay let's say also suggestion the
next suggestion is let me go to star container display flex okay I got this icons as suggested
let's say if I want to increase this icons so as we know that our icons font size is something
applicable let's say I say that 3 rem okay now now comes let's say for firstly I let me add a
border to this container border radius of 1 rem also border of 2 0.2 rem solid black
okay cool now then there is something let's say if I want to give some padding to each of
this particular class whatever star we have let's say I have some styling to it now do you see here
there's something that we were doing when you click it it was orange color yellow in color that
something filling or gold in color then there's something changing okay let's address that one
and I want to see you something firstly we'll come to ratings count display in line rightly I
said but if you see here there is any change do you see anything change in my mouse do you
see cursor getting changed from this this particular key to hand key cursor is pointer
right let's let's make that okay cursor is pointer now also let me add some padding it
to it so that they look differentiated 5 pixel or 0.3 rem okay cool then we had let's say by
default right let's say by default I'll say that these are white in color by default okay let's say
gray does it look better by default gray okay fine no if I make it white guys here are the
completely you know they are erased so I'm using so instead of white star I was thinking to you
know instead of toggling this content in our text like as you suggest if I go there are two
ways to build this one one is like if I if I want to use an inner text I will be on click of each
things I will change using inner text like replace this 97 double 3 with 9734 or else I can play
around with the color of a CSS right on click of this thing fill this particular star with the
color I hope these two approaches are like one approach and this approaches are clear right one
is toggling the CSS class the other one is updating the divs in us inner content in a text now then
firstly what I'll do is like you know for identifying each child uniquely for identifying
each child uniquely and what I'll do is that I'll add a separate attribute which will help me to
identify which particular star or which particular value I'm clicking it because if you see here
there's a one use case if I click on three third star do you see first three are getting filled
if I click on first four four are getting filled right so that's each case that we have to handle
when you click one only one when I'm clicking for all the four from left should be filled it's
not only one thing okay so let me give someone a data index so as you know that we can give
a number of attributes as we want so I'm just adding an index to the stars like two in order
to identify better okay now I'll add as to then three then four then five once we have this now
comes the main rule so now this you have okay we have to fix something which is like H2 make
it H2 as display in line as does this fix as one thing we still left help me out this one
ratings and this number how can we address this one
okay one way to fix this one is like and if you don't want to do it using CSS always cut
and put it here inside this one okay this is one of the hack you can always use it okay now
because I when I'm trying why did we do this one is that yeah right Ashish one one why I have to
put this zero inside the span tag is because I need to access the count using ID and then
that's the reason why we have written this way okay now comes the actual part where I'm
adding script tag where our logic should be handled now so one of the suggestion I've
already got from Kiran was can we get put further for loop which goes from one to the number
represented by star click and this loop would change CSS of star according right Kiran agree
but now you guys help me out how would you approach actual logic part here
which all things I should get access to which all things I should get access to
think of which strategies would you get access to all stars and then span okay let's say I get
const star document document dot query selector all and I use star okay I got the star then also
I got const count document dot query selector inside this I can say since it's an ID I have
to say this account now a good I got access to both the elements now is what I should do
where would you add an event listener where would you add an event listener for each on the star
event listener okay so I just want you to think we have learned even propagation technique can
we leverage that one or we have to add it on individual item which one is more preferable
like this is a simple question like okay we can run a for loop on star also I agree let's say let's
build this both things star dot for each let's say each star that's how I make it this has a
stars once we get each star we can say that star dot add event listener inside this event listener
we are listening to click okay on click of this listener what we'll do it's a both ways like
propagation is better since event account is decreased right somewhere I agree with that but
let's build this way and then that way so that everyone have that understanding right okay once
only one event is listeners click to the container later I think I agree with you
Kiran as that some bit suggested both are you know standing with same point but here let's say
I've added event listeners to all of them now what should we doing it now let's say I have an event
here now can I know how can I know which index item is clicked just help me out with that one
let's see
inner text in the inner text I don't have any value right in the inner text I have only this one
do you see any identifier that I added in order to identify which item is being clicked
data index right data index how would you access the data index
so let's see can I do something like
index what I can do is that let's say I start I say a particular star event now this is the star event
whichever star user is clicking get attribute
the data index
let's see if we are able to get this output
okay star pardon me guys now let's see if this we are able to get the output I'll copy the url
I'll put it here
so I have added our listeners everywhere now once if I click this I'm able to get it I'm able to
get that index as expected right now
line 50 star spelling I've addressed that one okay now guys what's the next thing what's the
next thing do I have to again go through each of stars
like I have to run a loop for let i equal to zero then till till where I have to go till the index
right till I reach index less than when I start from zero with index or else let's say start from
first index equal to this one right
now
one thing I have to do here is that star dot on each of the particular out of the stars
I'll get access to this each of the star on this star which particular attribute will have classes
on an element which particular attribute will have classes like
I've got one answer yeah great guys classes do you remember this that we on class list we will be
able to get all the classes that we need for a particular hsv now here what we are supposed to
now here what we are supposed to do we are supposed to add a new css class which will
fill the particular star now let's say I have a css class called star and I say fill
I say that color should be good okay no I'll say that can you add the css
class okay
is that it
is class list is default element no on each element on each element you will be able to
access what are the amount of classes that are applied using class list like if you say
go here dev dot class list you should be able to do it but div is not defined here but
like I can show you
but that's how it works actually I can have to put the debuggers and show it to you but here
one thing guys one thing I want to show you is that let's say I click on
yeah I have an access let's say I go to script tag let's I'll show you this one how this thing
works let's say I have here I put debuggers here as of now okay now let's say I have this
debuggers now if I click it on this third point if I click it in this third point let's say for
what is the index value I got I got to the as third that's great okay one thing one mistake
can anyone help me out what is the one mistake that I've already did it
no index 2 is fine data type can you see what is the data type of index
in for loop I'm no no this index is showing in the string format right 3 as a string but it should
be a number right because we are iterating through the loop I should be less than index
but I shouldn't be less than any string value right are you able to see this case this bug
are you able to see this case this bug so this is how debugging helps you like I put a debugger
point you know that what is the issue that where you got stuck now let's say I update this one
as a pass int
okay once I do this let's say this is working fine though but it by default it converted that one
but now
let's let's redo this one okay let's redo this one now if you see I
got the index as three now I'll update this index has three now let's get
we go to the stars now if you see each star let's say if I get go and do here star
star starts dot index of one that's how I do this index of one and
class list when I do this class list do you see a particular class list called star you can see it
how can you see this one that already there is a star added this is where you will be able to
identify
I hope this is clear to submit
okay now once we got this now once we got this let's see what's happening
let's say if I go and do this dot add
now I'm making another mistake here if you guys see you have to suggest me what mistake I did it
I'm adding a star fill once I click a play another time I click a play I click a play again now
now does this particular star fill got applied
now firstly does this star fill got applied till here
no let's see what happened here do you see here there is some mistake that star
fill is applied but it is applied in a wrong way
okay are you able to find the mistake guys
right when I'm adding a class if you see I'm adding as a dot
dot star where I have to add as a only css class name okay once I do and fix this one
and then there's another mistake that when I'm moving it from the index I have to start from
0th index because the divs will start from 0th index for the class list also it works like a
start from 0th index okay now now let's say I click on this one three times now if you see
first star got good second got good third got good now now what if I click on two elements only two
elements I want to give two ratings now do you see in that third element is not uncolored how
can we address this issue how can we address first we need to remove the class list okay great
so I hope this point is clear to everyone like we have to remove a particular class first then
we have to do it for like everything right let's say I go from let's say
on the loop I run the loop from stars index instead of this one I say stars dot length
okay and I do remove that's it right now let's say this is working fine
from rating point of view if I click that's how I remove the debugger as of now three then I'm
clicking two then I'm clicking one then I'm four then three till five then two I hope this is clear
how this is working guys anyone any doubts till now like how we are able to add CSS particular CSS
class how we are able to remove that now now comes the ratings part how would you update this ratings
pretty simple straightforward anyone can get it help me out
do I need to have a counter really
okay let's say can I can I do this count dot in our text
right now let's say if I click this star do you see this rating got in automatically added
because this index is giving me the data attribute index a data index value which star you are
clicking I'm getting that value and updating it simple and straightforward right
now let's say I'm going to add this index right now let's say I'm going to add this index
simple and straightforward right
now now this is the approach one
but before I go to approach second I hope for this this how this problem is being solved using
this way is clear to everyone anyone having any doubts in the whole class
I hope everyone is clear right so if if this sort of question comes you would be able to solve
in interview confidently without a sweat on face or any mark
so every problem whichever lld problem you face in interview take it step by step create a HTML
create a HTML go to basic CSS then access those elements add eventlessness simple
with the sweat on the face yeah that pressure will be there but I'm just trying to say that
once you build HTML part right you will be confident when it comes to JS part
right now guys
now I have this one that what if you want to build the same logic using event bubbling concept
firstly we need to have access to the container right the star container
let's say I get an access to star container
okay document dot query selector then I have dot class star container
let's say I pick the star container now on this container I attach one add event listener
I attach one add event listener click event is clicked and I have to be
able to do everything inside this one now
inside this event how would I will be able to get the values is the trick
only one thing I have to get it is that only this thing
only this thing is the trick that I have to get it other things let's say other things I copy paste
it other things I copy paste it simple I say const index also
okay now
no
okay current target no but
how would you get out of that event event dot
just I'm trying to get that okay let's let's do this let's do this
one thing I'll do it here is that let's comment this part okay and let's do
comment this part let's console log event here for a second
and let's comment this logic also
now go back to this one let's say if I remove this all this parts and I click something like
this one I click first star now if you see it here if you go to target element let's say
we go to target now we have this element now here inside this target let's say we go to
firstly let's see
the no
inside attributes do you see this data index
does this data index gives us the value that we need let's see this okay
I apply here I go to console I clean it up I select this one now let's say
event say I print just event dot target dot attributes
okay let's say I still get attribute inside that I pass it as data index
is my job done still
can I leverage this one
okay now let's see if I try to click it on the other one let's say click on fourth element
and I try to print this fourth element I'm still getting it
okay now let me do that same logic
so just uncommenting this one event dot target dot get attribute of data index
removing this part
okay this is still working so guys I hope this approach event bubbling concept is also clear
right how did we approach this one anyone having any challenge understanding this one how did we
approach this one
I hope this part is clear now I want to talk about something is that do you really think
we should be listening to click event or it should be something like
once you hover over it it should be filling that one
it should be a click event or listening to click is the right way or hover would be like let's
let's explore a real time now let's explore something like amazon what could be there
like I don't need anything okay hover changes the CSS but if you see
but if you see okay I'm getting the overall ratings here
okay only while buying we can keep the rating right
we cannot give the rating okay top reviews can we write a review
do I have an access to review write a review
okay write a product review
so they're asking me contact details and all but so but what if okay IMDB
yeah IMDB is right example let's say I go to this one
let's say I pick some movie
have anyone watched this movie good to caram
did you guys like this
okay average won't be able to take it pardon me
so if I hover over it do you see this here it is working on hover
I mean I like Mahesh Babu so I don't judge it is it good or bad I'll watch
good amount of times even I like Salar movie because I like Prabhas too so it doesn't matter
whether it's good or bad
it now so do you see this like until I hover there's a one sort of event once I click it
the number is updated
but while I'm hovering over it so there are two types of event
the color filling and the color removing is working on I mean the CSS class ticker is working on
mouse over and mouse leave event
are you able to see this
color filling is happening on mouse over and only the count is updated
on click of click now let's say leave it everything
what if I come and tell you build this whole component would you be able to do this
okay straight forward right we know how to build a overlay
we'll be just moving it to the width and height or according to the viewport
we'll make it this z index as high we'll give some background color for the whole container
when we open it and just add stars like 10 stars and give a one big star and rating button okay
this is fine right you would be able to do this guys
no I'm just asking like from your idea because I'm giving a one homework
that homework would be like how would you do it on mouse hover and mouse leave
and just I'm trying to think like would you be able to replicate this one
like if you want to replicate this one how would you be able to do it
okay so that confidence we need it you see go anytime real-time application any website that
you see think like from now on whenever you see any website or anything just think of it like
if you're adding devs header or h1 tags h2 tags okay how they're doing it now if you see this one
this is pretty simple right add four five devs four five items then add different states make
them display flex flex horizontal add a border make it keep a border radius
right pretty simple and straightforward right you will be able to design this one also
this particular India United States United Kingdom Bangladesh Canada
so whenever you see any website right you should be able to think that hey what is
how this layout has been designed what it took behind the scenes to build this one so it
should be that easy for you to know like what how that is being done okay it should be that
straightforward because we are doing enough things and we will be also building in next class but
I just want to know that this part of today's class content is clear like how we approach
this both the things now I want to talk about one thing before I start explaining how we can debug
so Arun had added a question like how should we able to debug I won't be picking up in the doubt
session but I'll pick it in the class itself because it's important for one person to know
how do we do it okay right before I do it so one thing I have to call out is that two people might
not have attended it there's a one site that is built by some with do you remember this there's
something likely like have you seen this website earlier anywhere have you seen this
right this looks cool right so some with the party has built this one he has you know changed
there was also an extra requirement of filtering the stars he has done that part so from now on
this is something looks like cool to me better to me okay now I hope you you also go and build
your own prototype of the project that we have built so that you can attach to the resume
second thing I've also pushed a code base related to my portfolio project where I want you to you
know edit your content as in the HTML part and link link to projects one is weather app
one is weather app and other one is your to-do list app or Kanban board
hope you will be doing this hope a few people will share me like the url some bit has done
done it hope you share it to me so that when we go on building the multiple projects across our
like cycle you will be able to have four or five projects added in your portfolio which you will
add it in a resume because when you put your scalar website you all portfolio website like you
generally show that how many dsa problems you have solved that's cool but when you have learned
front end or you have built full end-to-end language or build projects you should be also
able to show that I hope that you will be doing but one request I would make it is don't paste it
as it is because earlier batch also might have pasted that same projects wouldn't look good
add your own flavor of touch is that fine add your own sort of flavor so that you would be
your project might be looking like same functionalities but some css changes or
some additions that you can do is that is good enough I wouldn't say kiran like any project is
good enough or anything is good enough okay what I just want you to is think of it like whether
I'm clicking on this project I'm able to navigate to it you'll see I'm not able to go to that section
part still but I want you guys to you know get I'm trying to help you out with some part of it
so that you can build it the other things I'm there with you guys if you're not able to do
it anything we can we have the community and whatsapp group where we can like help each other out
if it is not possible you can message me directly if I'm available I'll try to take those questions
if I'm not I'll take it in the doubt session of the class
is that good enough kiran but I'm giving you a part of a code which you can edit and you can
add it like let's say get in touch on flick of the send how would you click off send how would
you make a function call like that will learn further when you when you go further and you know
send to your particular email id okay this information then same thing like how on click
of this let's say this other calculator shopping card or to to list I want you to edit this container
and show it like how can you do it these are the different containers I gave like about you about
yourself section the links you can add maybe if you want to add a picture then you can add a
project that you have done it okay add much of the content that you can but I've given a basic
prototype that you can do it okay great guys so if this is clear now I'll come to actually how
can you do the debugging part now so please pay a focus here guys now if you see one thing I'm
doing is like this is a source tab where I'm trying to debug it now I'll show it today in
how do you do it in browser I'll come to come back in future cases when I how you can do it in
visual studio code but now if you want to debug anything here firstly you you have this control
p or command p button I'm in macbook so I'm using macbook once you do command p whatever by default
whatever by default source code is there that you will be able to see here like you can search the
file names like I have star rating file name I'll be able to search it let's say if I have this
counter file no I don't have it because I loaded on this particular inside this classes javascript
star html in this particular thing I have only this one file I can open that file using command
is that point here how can you access your file firstly okay once you are able to access it now
once your code is loaded so what I can do is that mainly when you're debugging it you are trying to
in windows it is I think control p not control p but windows windows p I guess windows button you
can check that okay but it's suffix is p that is I can show a little
okay search button just search okay now what I'm doing only mostly will be trying to debug the
code part now let's say on this buttons right the line of code what I'm trying to do is that
I'm clicking on any of the line now let's say if I click on this line 67 or numbers when I'm
clicking on this numbers on the right side you will be able to see that where you have added
firstly you know this debuggers you can also delete this debugger if you want okay or else you can
also add it okay now also you can like you can write down the conditions if you want this is
really rarely I use it because I added conditions directly in the console log
okay I leverage console log I don't really add the conditions here
like in order so it's up to you but let's say I remove this debugger again I add it again
I hope these points are clear how can you add a debugger firstly
okay I see one thumbs down
we'll start
Krishna like I'm just selecting the number now when I select this number by default a debugger
is added to those particular lines and you'll be able to see all the debuggers on the right side
here below the breakpoint section okay if you want to remove the debugger either you can click
on that same line again or else you can click this cross button okay same thing now on whenever
a particular line of statement a code is getting stopped then you can add a conditions if you want
to add up whatever like if you want to test something like you want to do like let's say
console dot log of index now you can add this condition here okay now let's say if I refresh it
and I click this one
it will try to execute that particular point but I'm what I'm saying is that never use this way
like whatever condition I have used it here don't write that way but if you want to play around
if you want to play around right
if you want to play around with anything what you can do is like once you put the debuggers always
you if you want to if you want to if you want to write if you want to play around with the
like application now once you put the debuggers refresh this page once you refresh it or launch
the code then you will be able to apply the logics now once I click star button this part of code
will get executed now what you can do is at runtime right at runtime whatever values are there you
will be able to access everything now let's say in the memory if you see in the memory whatever in
this memory you can see here you will be able to access all the elements inside the console if I
want to access event I will be able to access event now in the memory I have also the value index
I'll be able to access index okay now similarly you also have the values like
since index is not yet loaded values and available once index is loaded once I click a play here so
there are two ways of doing it once you click a play the next time debugger will stop at the place
where you have the debugger point I mean the code execution will stop whenever you have the next
debugger point like let's say click a play it will stop at this point it won't stop at the for loop
okay this point is clear how this play button affects and how would you be able to access
all the values which are present in memory okay these are the items present in the memory that
you can see and even if you want to also check the call stack you can also leverage that and see that
now this is it guys nothing much you add a debugger's point this is like debugging any part
of the code you can do it on lead code you can do it on your code bases or anything
just add the debugger's point when you click a play it will go to the next debugger if you go to
the you can use all these functions like you can use this function to go to the next line
like it will go to if you see that when I click this one it will go line by line it will go to
for for the condition then it will execute next line so whatever the step by step if you want to
execute the code you can do this if you want to go inside this class list remove how it is working
you can click it inside okay if there's a library function added it will go inside that library
okay you have to explore all of these buttons but I am explaining on top level once you click a play
it goes to the next debugger and if you want to remove it you can remove it here cross button
or you can double click here which will remove that okay I mean click and re-click that's it
then if you want to disable all the debuggers just disable using this button once you disable
and you click a play everything will be loading as as you want I hope this point is clear a basic
level of debugging once you keep practicing this thing you will be able to get this case
is this clear Arun and everyone I I want everyone to explore this one so that you will be getting
hands-on it will take time and do you think what the way I was able to get start.html I'll be able
to get Amazon code complete Amazon code on here in my network tab
do you think it is possible
do you think it is possible to get the whole code base
so what happens here guys is that you know once your code is deployed right at the at the scale
happens here guys is that you know once your code is deployed right at the at the scale of this
like site mostly they combine these files into smaller you know files like let's say if I try
to filter html or let's say index.js if you see there are many index.js
but you don't have access to any of this code
let's say I go to this one I go to this one you can explore the how they have deployed everything
okay gif files and everything whatever downloaded things are getting downloaded are present here
now this min.js if you see this is the code they have written and this is like they have written
in some other language but it is minified it is bundled and minified to convert it into this file
min.js now this is the logic you can see there's a lot of javascript written inside this this is
system generated or you can say webpack bundled this is the logic you can see there's a lot of
or you can say webpack bundled we'll see all of them how this thing works but at real time
you might not be able to debug the application at only development time because at development
time we are trying to load the whole source code and I'm trying to experience this one we have not
bundled completely now let's see if I if I go to some with netlify app are we able to see this
project code now but if do you see this I'm able to access some bits code completely
this project code now this is not a right way right if I want to
copy all some bit css I can do it right away
okay so I'm with your project is copied now I'm sorry for this
I didn't want to show this one but yeah that's that's how
it works if you want to build this right if you want to build you have bundlers you have bundlers
let's say friend and bundlers
so
okay there are many js bundlers which are available okay one is like have you heard this
keyword called okay I'll start the doubt session guys I hope I've answered how debugging is
is done right can I start a doubt session guys because content is covered I'll keep on talking
uh and can I mark Arun your question has answered
I don't know marking your question has answered
okay great now so have you heard this webpack earlier so webpack is one of the most
uh used bundler in our whole projects they we use this bundler like what happens is like
a project will have n number of html files n number of js files n number of css files because
you cannot really build whole amazon or flipkart or netflix in three files right one css one
html and one js file do you guys agree with that point at least like only three files if you write
down it will be more than 50 60 thousands of code now if you write down that way it is really
difficult so what does this this do is you have n number of files you have to merge all of those
files into basic three files which is one index file one index css file one index js file now for
doing this thing right for understanding all the code and bundling together is being done by this
part of packages now webpack is one of the thing which handles it for that one you have to give a
certain set of configuration what is the entry file okay how can you access that entry file
okay what is a path then how you want to use loaders okay mode browser compatibility
a list of configurations you have to write okay then it will be able to bundle it then you have
browserify i have parcel fusebox fusebox i never heard it roll up roll up is really common
explore this one also guys roll up
wheat wheat.js is a really great one
but there was something new thing that got
uh jspopular frameworks let's say
no there's a one website
so
react is anyways on the top stack or survey but this is not the site
okay
now okay uh they have awsl lrt no i don't really know okay they might have
i'll get you one site guys where you will be able to see
the actually things
free code camp popular
okay free code pack camp 30,000 stars i don't want to go to org but where is this github repo
they have more than
three eight three stars now if you go to different things
let's say i go for web what i have it in web
cd npm i so this is a basically react project you can explore this one
but why so many stars what they are building here
so you have issues of 290 okay you have 71 pull requests which are open you can always
know there's something called babel also we'll explore react does this right
no react is just a library we'll see what all things are there what or not now we'll come to that
everything guys
but you see this free code camp is one of the most popular website where you can add
if you want to do open source you have to do this
there are some awesome uh front-end projects that are being built if you are good with really
HTML CSS JS right uh you will be able to do this now if you see if you want to learn system design
design in future they have built one project called system design okay this looks cool
best you see this designer hash map least recently used cache call center deck of cards
parking lot chat server circular array everything is available explore this explore this
really popular github website so you can find all the code that you need in github itself
and also that's something you will be learning in future maybe sometime later
cap theorem and everything this is really cool and people pay a really great amount of money
for this one on educative.io i've shared this link i was also just exploring see if you go to
explore what are the possible uh facebook react is also one of the popular github repo
if you want to see how where react code is there this is a github repo where
all the code is there now if you see it's had having a 219 uh k like stars and if you see it
is having more than 1.2k problems still present in this uh library it has more than 417 pull
requests which are open that need to be merged so every day continuous developments keep on going
okay anyways i'll keep on talking but i'll address the question
need help with css position like if we add position css how can we make it
stable when page is minimized or maximized
uh some with uh how pages uh okay uh yeah like are you meant to say that uh for example in my
to-do app search icon works good at 100 window okay okay let's let's do that
this one
okay uh for this okay when i reduce this one is it
i think you have used your vh and that one right percentages for the model
so that will be automatically calculating here not there then in search bar okay
if i minimize further just a second
okay this icon you mean to say that search icon
okay now
for that one uh let's let's see what's the css apply let me close this one first
okay position relative uh okay that because you have used with respect to parent uh you have
kept it that here now
let's say inside this container if i go here uh you have the solid icon
no
you have made it that one like let's say then you have
uh if you want to move with respect to this one uh you also have to make a simple position as
absolute then you have to give the exact ratio like let's say if i have this position absolute
always added now let's see if this is moving as expected it's coming inside as of now okay
okay i am having this one but i have to make it let's say for this one container you have always
our display justify content center uh which is uh let's say if i use space around
one
and i remove this okay this is fine but now
okay i'll check on that and come back somewhere because i have to figure out
how we'll be able to do that not getting any direct ideas but if anyone is having any better
ideas uh can you go to css file okay uh let's let's let's go to this css file
in my local
okay last
search icon bottom left you have added two fields like
okay but again uh see when you are minimizing it with respect to
it is always you have given in terms of percentages that's cool thing
you're having a search icon class right let me see search icon class you're having this
field value given now that's fine but if i'm reducing it further if i
you're having this bottom left that's fine
now the problem here in terms of percentages happening is that uh that the screen percentages
somewhere if you see it here the screen percentages for earlier 23 percent of value is something
and 60 percent value is something but now uh when you uh fix this uh like let's say if you fix this
using vh and let's say you fix this with uh because percentages are not supporting really
because if i tell you this uh if i minimize this one the 23 percent for uh the larger screen is
different uh when you reduce the screen size 23 percent is different
we can fix this by media query update right uh media query will support it but uh what if
you want to address it directly at one shot uh do this
well how we can if i if i use any other units if i use any other units like let's say uh
now since we are moving with respect to uh this parent right search container let's say
we are moving with respect to this container itself
then we are positioning this bottom end
now i made this container position uh position relative then i'm using this to make it uh look
up move around the question with this one that's cool but how would we make it in terms of other
than percentages
this
if i can i use
let's say if i use uh
bottom is fine bottom is always ticking it right bottom is always ticking it until i reduce it
until i reduce it from uh this way bottom is ticking it now if i uh reduce the screen size
by this way uh still my bottom is reducing it uh sticking it now i have to only fix something is
left one let's say instead of left uh what if i give right value as always 40 percent
40 percent or let's say if i increase it by further reduce it say 38 now but if i
no it it still doesn't matter because we have to move according to the sibling
vertically it's absolute search parent okay
okay let's say uh we don't want to play around with something like
a relative absolute let's say i go there i remove this absolute value also
no
no the search container uh let's say i just make it as center
and
align items center fine no
no uh also i say that i also have some gap of five pixel or let's say i make it
30 pixel then if i do this
this will work fine but uh if this will work fine but but but i have to do another thing which is
aligning that vertically in between this is working some bit like i'm just using a gap
property to move it across a common gap between each of the element but also
like rather than using position relative or absolute for this one if you want to
use it for resizing uh this will work better
but the only thing i'm thinking is like of you okay you have padding on the top is it
padding on the top uh how come the padding i can see the padding here
inside the search box container input tag element you might be having a default values coming up
let's say uh padding top i try to make it zero so that everything looks alike
i try to make it zero so that everything looks aligned
and margin is something like or else let's say i go to this class search icon i also add
in order to make it look even i have to replicate that same css which are added there let's say i
go and have a padding of seven uh
pixel and let's say i also have a margin of
one pixel now if i have this i don't need a padding uh margin would work fine
but i have to increase it further only i have to need it in the margin top
to make it center aligned but let's see if this is working fine
this is addressed uh up to good extent some bit
do you agree with my point or do you uh do you have to uh say anything on this i just uh
uh address this issue using gap property which will help me from the flex but using even even
but using even even using this position right even using this position absolute and relative
we should be able to figure out because flex was not always available in nature right uh
there might be a way but i am not it's not clicking me direct i'll check on that and come back
okay uh so yeah filter by text is also having same issue okay uh
uh okay that also you can check like you can always use list of such things but
this will help you to figure it out okay
cool guys uh kabir has one question yeah kabir please go ahead i'll take your question
uh do you want me to unmute or you'll be sharing it
okay i'll do you unmute you
please go ahead kabir
hello can you hear me
uh i've unmuted you can you speak
hello
hello yeah uh kabir
try speaking i'm not able to hear you can anyone hear okay i'm not able to hear guys uh just a second
uh
pardon me i'm not exactly able to hear because if you see if i try to remove my headphones
okay
hello
so
you
Okay, not exactly sure I was not able to listen to Kabir with my headsets on I tried to remove
then I was able to hear his voice but when I was trying to speak you were not able to
listen maybe some glitch guys I'll have to recheck but Kabir if it's possible write it
down or else I'll connect with you offline if it's big one how do you want me to take it up
right let's connect offline we can connect on call works well okay want to show some
okay you share me the link show me the link or else we can connect the offline we'll connect
post this class Google meet link I'll join that
great guys in that case can we end the sessions today's session I hope you all
have enjoyed and learned a bit from machine coding point of view we just got but I wanted
to give you one thing that maybe I'll give it in next class itself for practicing purpose right
what are the most interview asked questions how where can you get those things from LLT
perspective so I'll share that do you know this person he is a front-end senior front-end
developer currently he's working with Atlassian he was used to work with coin I think coin DCX
okay these are the set of many challenges that you can solve with JS you have a set of questions
that you can solve we have solved coin counter and we might have also stopped a solved a question
of ratings but there are some least of questions that you can solve like star rating display we
have solved whether app we have build okay we have covered few set of questions I view have to
like footer we have covered you have to see like what you can build and what you're not okay these
are the least of which that you have to be okay work around and built it simple HTML then you are
I'll talk on this in next class okay there for now chill and just try to you know solve if you
have any assignments complete them and let's meet back on the Thursday guys I think I have
tried to wanted to make this session extended to us 36 minutes okay so you guys then good night
take care take rest and meet back on Thursday so guys can I end the session give me thumbs up one
final thumbs up shall always bye bye